A Guide to the Papers of the Williams Family, 1798 (1802-1972) 1987
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Murat Willis Williams Papers
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - Correspondence of MWW 1976 Mar - 1979 Apr, 7 folders (Box 11)
      - Correspondence of MWW 1979 May - 1987, 6 folders (Box 12)
      - Correspondence of MWW n.d. (Box 13)
    - Topical
      - Correspondence of Murat Willis Williams with his parents 1923-1949, 7 folders (Box 13)
      - Correspondence of MWW with his parents 1950 - 1960 August, n.d., 7 folders (Box 14)
      - Correspondence of MWW with his parents n.d. (Box 15)
      - Letters of MWW to his parents--Woodberry Forest 1920, 1928-1932, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Correspondence of MWW with his parents--University of Virginia 1929-1935 (Box 15)
      - Correspondence of MWW--University of Virginia 1931-1968, n.d., 3 folders (Box 15)
      - Correspondence of MWW--University of Virginia 1932-1935, n.d., [folder 4: mold-damaged items] (Box 16)
      - Letters of MWW to his parents--Oxford University 1937-1939, 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Letters to MWW--Oxford University 1936-1937, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Letters to MWW--Oxford University 1938, n.d., folder 3 (Box 17)
      - Letters of MWW to John Page Williams (chiefly from El Salvador) 1928-1976, n.d., 3 folders (Box 17)
      - Letters of MWW--Spain 1932-1944, n.d., 3 folders (Box 17)
      - Letters to MWW--Richmond News-Leader 1935-1948 (Box 18)
      - Letters of David McCord Wright to MWW 1937-1975, n.d., 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Letters of MWW to Alastair F. Buchan 1939-1975 (Box 18)
      - Correspondence of MWW--El Salvador 1947-1964, n.d., 5 folders (Box 18)
      - Letters from Magada, Miona & Radu Miclesu (Budapest, Romania) to Murat & Joan Williams 1950-1958, 1969-1976 (Box 19)
      - Letters to Murat & Joan Williams from Bucharest, Romania 1951-1953 (Box 19)
      - Letters to MWW--Salonika, Greece 1954-1955 (Box 19)
      - Correspondence of Joan Williams 1941-1953, 5 folders (Box 19)
      - Correspondence of Joan Williams 1954-1979, n.d., 3 folders (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1937-1975 (Box 20)
      - Letter Fragments 1966, 1974, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Foreign Service
    - American Foreign Service Association Symposium 1964-1965 (Box 20)
    - Foreign Service Association: Memorial Plaque 1965 (Box 20)
    - Department of State/Foreign Service [1 of 2] 1944-1981 (Box 20)
    - Department of State/Foreign Service [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 21)
    - El Salvador--Newsclippings re MWW 1961-1965 (Box 21)
    - El Salvador--Photographs of MWW & miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 21)
    - El Salvador--Speeches and articles of MWW 1961-1964 (Box 21)
  - Political Papers
    - Correspondence and related papers of MWW re Virginia Democratic politics 1965-1970, 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Correspondence and related papers of MWW re Virginia Democratic politics 1971-1972, n.d., 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Virginians for McCarthy--Correspondence 1967-1969, n.d., 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Virginians for McCarthy--Campaign Material 1967-1968, n.d., 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Virginians for McCarthy--Newspaper Articles 1968 (Box 22)
    - Congressional Campaigns--Miscellaneous Correspondence 1965-1972, n.d. (Box 22)
    - Congressional Campaigns--Miscellaneous 1968-1970, n.d. (Box 23)
    - Congressional Campaign Correspondence: Albemarle County 1970 (Box 23)
    - Congressional Campaign Correspondence: Charlottesville to Page County 1970, 5 folders (Box 23)
    - Congressional Campaign Correspondence: Rappahannock to Winchester 1970, 3 folders (Box 24)
    - Campaign Scrapbook 1970 Sep-Oct, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Press Releases 1970 (Box 24)
    - Campaign Expenses and Donations 1970, 1972 (Box 24)
    - Campaign Publicity Materials 1970, 1972 (Box 24)
    - Campaign Scrapbook 1970, 1972, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Campaign Scrapbook 1972 (Box 25)
    - Press Releases 1972 (Box 25)
    - Publicity Photographs 1972 (Box 25)
    - Williams for Congress checks 1972 (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous Files
    - Biographical Sketch and news article re MWW ca. 1972, 1978 (Box 25)
    - Financial and Legal Papers 1939-1976 (Box 25)
    - Genealogy 1914, 1947, 1953-1980, n.d. (Box 25)
    - Military Service of Murat W. Williams and related items 1940-1945 (Box 25)
    - Francis Pickens Miller: Letters & materials re publication of Man From The Valley: Memoirs of a 20th Century Virginian 1968-1972, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous 1901-1948 (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous 1961-1984, n.d. (Box 26)
    - Newspaper Clippings 1955-1974, 1987, n.d. (Box 26)
    - Oral History Interview of MWW w/letter (Columbia University) 1979 (Box 26)
    - Photographs--Williams Family 1917-1972, n.d. (Box 26)
    - Photographs--Miscellaneous 1939, 1962, n.d. (Box 26)
    - School Papers: Murat W. Williams 1921-1938, n.d., 2 folders (Box 26)
    - School Papers: Williams Family 1923-1969 (Box 26)
    - Speeches and writings of MWW 1940, 1965-1984, n.d., 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Speeches and writings: Miscellaneous 1947-1980, n.d., 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Speeches and writings: Williams Family 1959, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Virginia Center for the Creative Arts 1974-1975 (Box 27)
    - Fielding Lewis Williams 1962, 1984 (Box 27)
- Lewis Catlett Williams
  - Woodberry Forest High School Certificates of Disctinction, June 9, 1892
    - Civic Sections, Intermediate Examination (Oversize M-18)
    - Civic Sections, Final Examination (Oversize M-18)
    - English, Intermediate Examination (Oversize M-18)
    - French, Intermediate Examination (Oversize M-18)
    - French, Final Examination (Oversize M-18)
    - Latin, Intermediate Examination (Oversize M-18)
    - Latin, Final Examination (Oversize M-18)
    - Orthography, Intermediate Examination (Oversize M-18)
    - Orthography, Final Examination (Oversize M-18)
    - Trigonometry, Intermediate Examination (Oversize M-18)
  - University of Virginia Certificates and Diplomas
    - M.A., Mathematics 1894 June 13 (Oversize M-18)
    - B.A., German 1895 June 12 (Oversize M-18)
    - M.A., Latin 1895 June 12 (Oversize M-18)
    - B.A., Political Economy 1896 June 17 (Oversize M-18)
    - B.A., English Literature 1897 June 16 (Oversize M-18)
    - B.A., Moral Philosophy 1897 June 16 (Oversize M-18)
    - B.A., History n.d. (Oversize M-18)
    - Bachelor of Arts Diploma 1897 June 16 (Oversize M-18)
    - Master of Arts Diploma 1897 June 16 (Oversize M-18)
    - Appointment commission, Lewis C. Williams, to the Board of Visitors of the University of Virginia 1922 March 13 (Oversize M-18)
- Murat Willis Williams
  - Diploma, Woodberry Forest School 1931 June 4 (Oversize M-18)
  - "University of Virginia College of Arts and Sciences Third Term... Distinguished Students;" includes Murat Willis Williams 1931-1932 (Oversize M-18)
  - Certificate, Lieut. Murat Willis Williams, U.S.N.R., "Solemn Mysteries Of The Ancient Order of The Deep" (Latitude 00000) 1944 Oct 13 (Oversize M-18)
  - Appointment certificate, Murat W. Williams as a secretary in the diplomatic service, signed by President Harry S. Truman and attested by Secretary of State George C. Marshall 1947 Feb 18 (Oversize M-18)
  - Appointment certificate, Murat W. Williams as a Foreign Service Officer Class Four, signed by President Harry S. Truman and attested by Secretary of State George C. Marshall 1947 Feb 18 (Oversize M-18)
  - Certificate from the President of El Salvador recognizing Murat W. Williams as United States consul 1947 Jul 14 (Oversize M-18)
  - 11Certificate, "Domain Of The Golden Dragon, Ruler of the 180th Meridian"--MWW 1954 May 11 (Oversize M-19)
  - Appointment certificate, Murat W. Williams as a Foreign Service Officer Class Two, signed (autopen?) by President Dwight D. Eisenhower and attested by Secretary of State John Foster Dulles 1954 Dec 3 (Oversize M-18)
  - Photographic copy of a Fred O. Seibel cartoon, "Winds of Change," inscribed for MWW 1966 Jul 17 (Oversize M-18)
  - Certificate, MWW as a Fellow of the International Consular Academy 1970 Sep 1 (Oversize M-18)
  - "Plans & Specifications of Servants Room Addition At 5401 Cary St. Road--Edward G. Frye Jr. Builder" n.d. (Oversize M-18)